Alfonso Gonzalez

💌 alnimag3@icloud.com 👂 Seattle WA / Rincon PR 🔭 Website 🙀 LinkedIn 🔘 GitHub

SUMMARY

Recent career transition into software engineering after 13 years as an owner and operator of restaurants. Proactive, personable problem solver, eager to put my new skills to work. Fast learner, enjoying the journey into the tech field. I believe that honest and open communication can solve most problems that arise in the workplace. I have a few years of experience in the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. Fluent in English and Spanish and able to multi-task and work with a wide range of personality types. I desire a position that would provide targeted mentorship to help me expand my skillset.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

• Languages and Frameworks:

JavaScript, Ruby, Node.js, HTML/CSS, SQL, Sinatra, MiniTest, Jekyll, Liquid

• Technologies:

GitHub, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Sublime

PROJECTS

• **Todo List,** code on GitHub □

A tested Heroku application that allows users to create to-do lists. Created using Ruby, Sinatra, and PostgreSQL.

Tic Tac Toe Game, code on GitHub □

Simple tic-tac-toe game for the command line created with Ruby

Rock Paper Scissors game, conde on GitHub ☑

A simple RPS game for a school project created with Ruby

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Owner/Operator, La Isla Cuisine Restaurants

Jan 2005 – Nov 2018

• Hired, trained, and managed multiple teams of employees while building the business from the ground up.

Seattle

- Created an environment that focused on teamwork, leading by example, and mentorship while encouraging a sense of ownership for my employees.
- Learned to be proactive about trying to solve the day-to-day problems that come from a dynamic environment

Owner/Operator, The Valley Cafe Restaurant

Launch School 🗷

Mar 2015 - Oct 2017

Ellensburg

2020 - 2022

- Transitioned into a technology-based system from an analog ticketing system • Implemented a training system that taught existing employees to train new hires

EDUCATION

• Rigorous mastery-based, multi-year, full-stack Software Engineering curriculum for

Programming foundations, Object Oriented Programming, Networking and Database foundations.

Bachelors degree in Science, *University of Massachusetts* □

1998

Amherst

alnimag3@icloud.com 1/1